How to create a customised system for your M3?
We have been working on the M3 system for a long time.
We created our configuration, our database,
our information about suppliers, customers, items.
We ordered the item, we received it on the stand
and we managed it within our warehouses.
Now we will move a little further.
We will skip production and move on to sales.
The module that we see between the M3 and the M3,
which we see between production and sales,
is a warehouse module that will not be practically different
from managing reserves and ready-made products
from what we have already discussed before.
But what about the sales module?
In the sales module we want our product,
which we have in the warehouse,
and it doesn't necessarily have to be a product
that is ready to be sold to the customer.
When we have our reserves
and even if we want to sell our stock of cardboard,
or raw material, or any other stock we have,
we can do it.
Let's go to the company structure
and we can distinguish two basic things.
Two basic transactions that can take place during sales.
It can be group sales,
i.e. between our divisions within our entire group,
or external, out-of-group,
i.e. from each division to an external customer.
The process of sending, preparing goods and sales
does not differ when it comes to the performance of the system,
but the settings differ,
because with our customers we will have different settings
than when we accept the settings of group sales.
When selling goods,
we will rely on the already defined settings
in the environment in which we work
during the discussion of activities in M3.
I will show you in a moment
how to sell goods to another division.
As I said, the only thing that we can do
is to sell goods to another division.
As I said, the only thing that will differ
between sales,
between divisions and external customers,
will be the choice of the appropriate contractor
when creating a transaction,
and the already saved configurations in the system
will properly control our activities.
The procedure of sending and selling
our stock to the client
and regardless of whether it will be a group or external customer,
I encourage you to start by examining our stock,
what we will actually want to sell.
Let's go to the MWS060 application
and find the goods we have received.
Let's assume that we want to sell
this stock that we see here
about this specified flight,
i.e. PZTEST02.
We have copied the number of our product,
copy the flight number right away,
it will be very useful for us.
Now let's go back to our products for a moment.
Let's go back to our structures for a moment.
What do we need to send this product further?
If we already know what product we want to send,
what product do we have to prepare?
In fact, we need to enter the order of sale.
We have already entered the purchase order
and now we have to create a new one.
We have to create a new purchase order from our store.
Let's assume that LISAKI DEUTSCHLAND
will want to buy a stock from LISAKI POLSKA.
Now LISAKI DEUTSCHLAND has sent their purchase order to us
and we have to enter this purchase order
as a sales order.
Only when we do this and enter the order line,
the order line of this sales order,
will we be able to allocate our goods,
our stock,
our stock of the purchase order
and send them.
To do this, we return to M3
and prepare the OIS300 application.
The OIS300 application contains a collection of sales orders.
These are customer orders
that are introduced into our system
and on the basis of which we will perform
the movements leading to the delivery of the shipment
and the sale of our stock.
Of course, depending on how we want to sort the list of these orders,
we choose the type of sorting we are interested in
and the type of view with which
before starting work in the sales module,
it is worth getting acquainted.
Everyone will simply find the right view for themselves.
We will go to our division.
We now have a list of all sales orders
for our division.
And to enter the sales order
on the basis of the purchase order
that we received from our customer,
we go to New Order
and in turn we complete all the data
that we need to conduct the transaction.
We start to complete the data
required to conduct the transaction.
We complete the customer's number.
When the goods will reach the customer,
we assume that it will be on June 30th
and the customer's address.
We can now enter the number of the customer
and the number of his purchase order.
Let's assume that it will be this number.
When we have entered the data we need,
things like the type of customer order
and the rest will be automatically displayed,
because during the creation of the order,
we must have already entered the customer's card.
The customer's data will be completed,
which was also possible during configuration
in the CRS 620 application.
All this information was added to it.
We click Control 1,
then F12
and Enter.
To proceed further.
The card opened.
The first order header card,
in which we complete the exact data
regarding the currency,
regarding the price and conditions,
the payment details.
If everything is correct,
what we expect to appear on this card,
we click Next, Enter.
We go to the order details.
In this case, we discuss here in turn
what is responsible for what,
what parameter we can here,
enter and what it will mean
for the whole creation of the transaction.
The data that is already here,
introduced, which we see here,
are the basis of what we have completed
during the previous configurations.
If only our configuration assumed that
we can, during the creation of the order,
sales,
edit this information,
we can do it here.
At the beginning, we make sure
whether we have indicated a good
warehouse from which we will,
from which we will issue our product,
what are our references.
In this place, I usually complete
the name and surname of the person
working on this warehouse,
so that she knows that it is addressed to him.
It is also worth entering here
the person or department
that appears on the purchase order
that we received from the client.
Based on this contact and the order number
of the purchase order
that we received from our client,
it will be possible to immediately identify
and facilitate the accounting
of the entire transaction later.
We can add a person who will be
and who is responsible for the sale
to this particular client,
unless there is a person
who is concerned properly
about the payment list,
felt more comfortable
in
responsibilities.
We will see other possibilities that can be configured in relation to payment methods depending on the transaction.
Next, we will specify the amount of days to be paid, the terms of the invoice, VAT, taxes and, going further, the key dates.
The dates that we see here are the first and last date of the possibility of accepting this order.
The second is the date of the payment of the payment by our client.
If there is such a possibility and the client gives us the possibility of delivery, let's say, between Monday and Friday of the next week, we can supplement this range here.
Or we can specify a specific day depending on the amount of orders with the client.
As we have set in this case, it will be only and exclusively 30.06.
A fairly important parameter is also the possibility of marking this checkbox, abnormal demand.
This parameter, if it is marked, will be information for the system.
If, of course, we use automation, calculations and planning of stock, sales, shipments and maintenance of our stock,
we can mark that this is an order.
We can also mark the number of orders that are not to be counted in all these calculations.
Perhaps it will happen that it will be an additional request or it will be a small fraction of the client's needs to meet his needs.
We will not want it to have any impact on the customer's business.
We will also check the number of orders that are to be counted in the system.
We select the method of transport, whether it will be road, air, train or ship.
We also select the delivery terms, i.e. how the goods and everything will be picked up.
Delivery at place is a parameter indicated by us on this countermeasure.
However, we know what the delivery status is.
If the delivery status is not selected by our customer, we will add the EXW parameter.
If we have already selected our delivery method, we can specify where it is.
The location was indicated to us in connection with our previous configuration.
The address was also transferred from the first configuration card that we have just defined by entering the basic order data.
There is also a Delivery Specification option.
If we have additional ramps, storage places that we have configured in the system set within the address,
we can directly specify that this is the delivery address.
This goods should be unloaded at B square in ramp C40.
In addition, we can add a manual comment where it should be unloaded.
The goods that I send in this way most often go to ramp N1, so I will allow myself to enter this parameter.
The next settings are drawn from the original configuration and are appropriate for the transaction.
I press Enter and proceed.
At this point, the OS101 application opens.
This is an application that allows you to create a order link inside the order.
We will add the order line to our stock and provide the details of this line.
At this point, we will use our texts written in the note, i.e. our flight number, our article number.
We do not have to fill in the magazine here, because the magazine was indicated earlier.
What we can do right away if we go to this stage of creating a sales order,
we can immediately copy our order number to the note.
It will be very important.
Because thanks to this, we will find our order number in an easy way in the next steps.
We copy it.
It is safe now.
We forget.
And we complete the parameters of our line.
We paste the number of our article.
We check what the amount was.
We can also copy.
We paste.
We can enter units for sure.
We copied from our stock where there were basic units, i.e. pieces.
So here we will also copy the pieces.
Sales price.
And we enter if we do not use sales price indicators.
At this point I do not have such a configuration, so I will enter sales price.
But I will enter it as one.
I'll explain why in a moment.
We can also enter further for what unit it is the price.
Let's enter also for a piece.
And we can give, we must give the date of the order to the line.
As I mentioned, to each line in this configuration,
we can enter another delivery date.
Also, if we had selected the delivery range in the previous cards of creating this order,
we can then enter the date of the first delivery and the date of the last delivery.
It will be a visible range, a visible time space in which we will carry out individual deliveries of our lines.
If we have it prepared, we press enter.
We go to the details of this order line.
And the following information is compiled into these details.
First, we set the details of our delivery for this particular line.
The general address will be the same as for the entire order,
but we can, for example, if we have configured ramps or storage places in a given location,
we can indicate other parameters for each order line.
So 5 pallets will go to A square, 5 pallets to B square, the rest to C square, to such and such ramp.
Here we also confirm the delivery method, what type of transport it will be,
the dates of these deliveries.
And we have to indicate the route.
Why is it so important and what is the route parameter?
Since it is an Ex Works delivery, i.e. EXW,
we will choose the parameter corresponding to this option for our configuration, i.e. P10EXW.
Now, what is this route?
Let's open the answer.
What is the route?
The route, this parameter, this configuration of this parameter,
allows us to write down the actual traffic
that is
assigned to the road.
And we can also write down the route of the transport.
So, when we choose the route P10EXW,
we know how this product will be loaded,
how it will be unloaded
and how it will be implemented.
So P10EXW will be an Ex Works delivery,
but if it is a parameter that will not be a delivery type of Ex Works,
i.e. that our client takes it,
only from above it will be known which way this product will be driven,
i.e. let's assume P10Augsburg,
we know that then our product will be taken,
by the carrier,
will go a certain way,
through a certain city
and will reach the destination
through these locations indicated in this configuration,
in one way or another.
So it can be a connected transport,
direct load,
another route,
or as we chose here,
Ex Works,
i.e. it will be taken by the client
and we are not interested in how this product will be moved further.
In this configuration, if everything is correct on this card,
we click Enter
and we see that our line
of order
has already been created.
Now we have given that the price for a piece of cardboard
will be 1 euro.
This is how we chose during creating this order line.
We chose this way because by giving our sales price here,
we cannot detail it completely,
we cannot give the price,
for what amount is this price,
we can only give the total price and unit,
so I simplify it in this place as much as I can.
Always regardless of the currency,
there will be parameter 1 here
and the indicated unit of the price.
And only now,
by marking the line,
I enter through CTRL 2
by changing to the middle of this line
and at this point I complete the details,
i.e. the price,
I confirm the amount
and refer to the price
and in this place
I have the possibility
to give the price in detail
for our piece.
Because we have previously given the euro currency
and the price unit in the piece,
it will be 1 euro per piece.
And now we can indicate
how much the piece will cost.
And we can also specify
how much the price will be for each piece.
So for 1 euro
we can buy, for example,
1000 pieces.
If we set it like this,
we press ENTER,
we have been warned by the system
that in our configuration
we can set the maximum
price for the amount
to the amount of 999,
because we have configured
our item
that it can have
a maximum of 4
digits after 0
in the price configuration.
To change this,
we would have to go back
to the first MMS,
which we configured
at the very beginning.
Since we cannot
choose such a counter,
let's try to make
a counter in this system.
0.1
for 1 piece.
And at this point
we have
the price
of the piece
that we have
for each piece.
And now
the system has allowed us
to make such a change.
Of course,
we must know earlier
in what price frames
we want to move
to configure such
parameters
that will allow us
to manage prices
in such a way
that we can fit
in the frames
that we set
for each item.
I will finally change the price
to 0.001
for 1 piece.
We go further.
We can add
details
about the
item itself,
i.e. modify
its description,
its name,
give
alias number,
which was previously
assigned,
give the part number,
the number of another item
that can function
interchangeably for this item.
Once again,
we can configure,
give accurate data
from the purchase order
that we received
from our client.
And not only do we have
the possibility
to enter the order number,
but also to specify,
for example,
which is the line
from this order,
what is the value
to which this line relates,
which we are creating now.
Of course,
we can also
enter the number
of our contract,
if it exists,
our sales price,
if we use it.
If not, we go further.
We can also
enter the person
responsible for the sale,
also enter the reason
of the sale,
if it exists
and we want to configure it,
or we have configured it
earlier and we want to indicate it.
Of course,
we can also enter the date again,
the range,
if this order can be moving
and can come in a given
time period, for example, in a given week,
we can enter the date
and then we complete it
if there is such a need,
the country of origin
of this item,
which we enter
in our order line
and other business
settings.
If everything is correct,
we press enter,
go to the details,
calculations
regarding the line,
we can configure it again here,
we can enter the
VAT code
or the location,
the lot number
that we want to enter
during the allocation of this item,
if we want to
add, for example,
the use of a given reserve
to the warehouse.
Of course, we also confirm
the amount of the payment
if everything is correct.
We go further.
Here we have
an indication
to our
transport line.
We have already
passed all this
before.
We confirm
and our
line has been
properly configured
when it comes to
delivery details
and price details.
We see that
the price of the entire order
has changed significantly
and in the next steps
we will go to the allocation
to connect our reserve
under this line,
under this request,
under this order
so that we can
move on to the further
part of the
transaction of
sales and shipping of goods.
Thank you.
www.patreon.com